BU Records: Guardian Angels, Inclusive: 1958-1967, undated, Bulk: 1965-1967, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: Guardian Angels
Inclusive: 1958-1967, undated, Bulk: 1965-1967, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/101
Baylor University
9 folders
BU Records: Guardian Angels records include correspondence, literary productions and financial documents of the organization, which supports the Armstrong Browning Library on Baylor University's campus.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
The Guardian Angels of the Armstrong Browning Library was established under the direction of Dr. Andrew Joseph Armstrong, the founder and director of Armstrong Browning Library who also served as Chairman of the Baylor English Department from 1912 until 1952. The efforts to build the Armstrong Browning Library began in 1943, when Baylor’s 9th president, Pat Neff, offered Dr. Armstrong $100,000 towards the construction of a separate building to house the entirety of Dr. Armstrong’s Browning collections. Neff challenged Dr. Armstrong to raise the remaining funds for this project, which lead to the establishment of the Guardian Angels. The name for the patron organization of the library is a homage to Robert Browning’s poem “The Guardian Angel”. Following the formation of the Guardian Angels, the Guardian Angel Fund was established to enable the library to have consistent funding. The organization still exists today.
Scope and Content
The collections begins in 1958 and ends in 1967, with some undated materials. The collection contains organization records such as correspondence relating to dues, financial information, membership lists, and organization publications. Much of the correspondence is to or from Lois Douglas Murray, as she served as Acting Director of the organization during the 1960s.
Some materials in the collection were compiled by previous Texas Collection staff members over time and kept in subject files. These materials were added to the collection during processing.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, the organization of the collection was unknown. Currently, the collection is arranged alphabetically, comprising one series. I. Organization Records
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/101. Acquired 0-00-00
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Armstrong, A. Joseph, 1873-1954.
Subjects (Organizations)
Armstrong Browning Library.; Baylor University -- Finance.; Baylor University -- Societies, etc.
Subjects
Records (Documents); Strain, Lois S. (Lois Smith)
- Organization Records, 1958-1967, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Scope and Content
  This series contains materials related to the ongoing activities of the organization, including correspondence, financial information, materials relating to membership, and publications put out by the organization. This series is in average condition.
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Listing, 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Financial Information, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Membership Dues, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Membership Lists (1 of 2), 1958-1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Membership Lists (2 of 2), 1958-1966, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, 1966-1967, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Programs and Invitations, 1962-1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)